786 619 5583 • javi830810@gmail.com

Solutions-oriented developer. Computer Science Theorist.

Software Engineer, with 10+ years of experience in the software industry. Experience in HR Software, Education, Advertising, E-Commerce, and Communication Systems. Keen on minimalist solutions. Readability counts, explicit is better than implicit.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, C#, JavaScript, PHP, Ruby

Frameworks: SpringBoot, Express, ASP.NET MVC, Webapp2

Databases: MongoDB, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Redis, Memcached, Neo4J

Others: Docker, RabbitMQ, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, NetflixOS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at UltimateSoftware.

2015 – Present

- Designed and Implemented Messaging Platform. System to ensure multi-datacenter and multi-domain publishing of events. The platform offers encryption, RabbitMQ-Kafka transport and Schema Registry for messages.
- Designed and Implemented TMS. Multi tenancy System to hold the Company Customer information. Distributed, Elastic scaling. CQRS.
- Design and Implemented Monitoring Bots for our PROD applications. ELK and Sensu integration.
- Implemented Deployment pipelines. Rake and Chef development to implement Continuous Deployment.

Software Engineer at Kaplan, Inc.

2014 - 2015

- Designed and Implemented Scalebridge. Distributed Http Message Dispatcher System.
- Implemented KAPX. Learning Platform with video capabilities. Google AppEngine.

Founder/Software Engineer at XPLOT, Inc.

2013 - Present

 Designed and Implemented iMeet. Event Dispatching and design. Google App Engine Hosted.

^{*} References available upon request.

• Designed and Implemented Voiceflows. REST API to dispatch IVR and SMS. Twilio Integration. Deployed in Azure.

Software Engineer at JDA Software

2010 - 2013

- Designed and Implemented Shiftex. Work Shift Management Platform. message based and CQRS.
- Designed and Implemented Alerts. Highly performant and reliable Alert System distributing SMS, IVR, Email. CQRS Architecture

Software Developer at CIMEX Corporation

2005 - 2010

• CarlosTercero. Online store, with e-commerce capabilities, coupons, shopping cart, online checkout, payments etc.

EDUCATION

Graduate studies	Introduction to Artificial Intelligence Stanford University, USA	Dec 2011
Bachelor's Degree	Computer Science (GPA of 4.3 of 5) Havana University	Jun 2007

Find me on:

Github: http://github.com/javi830810
Twitter: http://twitter.com/javi830810

in LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/javi830810

StackOverflow: http://stackoverflow.com/users/71957/javi830810

^{*} References available upon request.